and now we're working to like point 1 of a mil accuracy because we've got laser cutters
そして今は、0.1ミルの精度でやっている。なぜかというと、レーザーカッターを買ったんだ。
we've got all the cutting jigs and it is all cut with hand by routers, but
僕らはカットするための治具を全て手に入れて、それはどれもルーターを使って手で切った感じだった。
you're working from a template that you digitally produced
だけど、デジタル的に作ったテンプレートを使って、仕事をすると、
and then once you've got that template you've got it forever.
一度手に入れたテンプレートはずっと使用する事が出来る。
Dave, you know, he's a proper old school carpenter joiner
デイヴは正しくオールドスクールな大工だ。
Everything's done by hand, and all proper oak and teak and ash
全て手で作る。そして全て適切に選ばれたオークやチークやトネリコの木材を使う。
and then we're in here, we're making speakers out of birch-ply and MDF
それで僕らはここで、樺材のベニヤ板や、MDFを使ってスピーカーを作っている。
and making furniture our of birch-ply and stuff like that
家具を樺材のベニヤ板で作ったりとか、そういう感じ。
and we're using like, laser cutters and all that, and he's using
僕らはレーザーカッターとかを使用していて、彼は
proper old school hand tools and stuff. And it's just really nice that it's side by side.
適切なオールドスクールの手作業の工具などを使っている。そのどちらもあるということが、本当に良いんだ。
You know you can't, you still need to have the hand tooling skills and stuff like that.
未だに手で工具を使用するようなスキルは必要なんだ。
You've got to understand the intricacies of putting it together
それを組み合わせる時の、その複雑さを理解する必要が有る。
and how it goes together, and what bits you're going to need,
そしてどういう風に組み合わさるかや、どんなビットが必要になるか、
and how to mix the hand skills with the CAD/CAM skills
それからどうやって手作業の技術と、CAD/CAMの技術を組み合わせるかもね。
and when I went to school, I went to Uni at Salford, eight or nine years ago
8年か9年前、僕が学校に行っていたとき、ソルフォードにあったUniに行ったんだ。
and they didn't have a laser cutter, they didn't have anything.
彼らはレーザーカッターを持ってなかったというか、彼らは何も持ってなかった。
They had a rapid prototyper which was the flour and water composite thing,
彼らはラピッドプロトタイピングのためのものを持っていて、それは、粉末と水を混ぜ合わせたような物だった。
like literally, you touched it and it went "PHOOOOSH" like that
文字通りには、さわったら、それはフーシュ（粉が飛び散る感じ）という感じだった。
and it was good, but now here we are 9 years later and the school I used to teach in
それは良かったんだけど、今は9年後だ。僕が教えにいっていた学校は、
used to have a dimension plotter and a 3D printer, like 2 laser cutters
ディメンジョンプロッターと、3Dプリンターを持っていた。2台のレーザーカッターとかね。
a CNC lathe, a CNC router - that's in the space of 9 years.
それからCNC旋盤や、CNCルーターとかもだけど、それはそのスペースに9年間あったものだ。
And then you've got 11, 12, 13  year old kids who do that type of thing
それで、11歳、12歳、13歳の子供たちと一緒にいて、その子供達はその年齢から、
right from that age all the way through.
この種の事をずっとやり始める事になる。
think the thing that made me realize how good and powerful it could all be
僕がそれらがいかに優れていて、パワフルかという事に気づいたのは
was when I started learning how to use 	Illustrator.
イラストレーターの使い方を学んでいるときだったと思う。
And it just made me go, all right! That was like a month ago taking me like a week to do.
そして僕はその方向で進む事になって、オールライト！な感じだった。なぜなら、それはまるで一ヶ月前に一週間かかった事が、
It's now taking me four hours. It just sort of made me go, huh, all right, yeah
今はたった４時間でできるようになったんだ。それはなんというか、僕を進ませてくれて、オールライト！な事だった。
it does make a lot of sense.
それには十分納得がいっている。